Inventory of the Edward J. Rozek papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- Court Case Materials, 1965-1995 (Boxes 63-71)
  - Letters to editor, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 15)
  - Responses to newspaper articles, 1980 (Box-folder 63: 16)
  - Colorado Daily, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 17)
  - Colorado Daily, 1983 (Box-folder 63: 18)
  - James Scott's letter to the Boulder Camera, 1983 (Box-folder 64: 1)
  - Campus press, 1983 (Box-folder 64: 2)
  - Response to Boulder Camera articles, 1983 (Box-folder 64: 3)
  - Beth's letter to Boulder Camera, 1983 (Box-folder 64: 4)
  - Collegiate Times, 1984 (Box-folder 64: 5)
  - Wiscombe article, 1984 February 5 (Box-folder 64: 6)
  - Rocky Mountain News, 1982-1984 (Box-folder 64: 7)
  - Copies of Silver and Gold Record, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 64: 8)
  - Copies of Boulder Camera articles, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 64: 9)
  - Copies of Denver Post articles, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 64: 10)
  - Letter to Boulder Camera, 1984 October 8 (Box-folder 64: 11)
  - "U.S. Can't Shape Events in China,", 1984 December 7 (Box-folder 64: 12)
    Includes copy of The Collegiate Times.
  - Correspondence between Beth MacParland and Mindy Franklin regarding court case, 1983 December 27 (Box-folder 64: 13)
  - Civil suit newspaper articles, 1985 May (Box-folder 64: 14)
  - National Review article, 1985 (Box-folder 64: 15)
  - Edward Rozek's deposition (copy), 1986 (Box-folder 64: 16)
  - Tom Borillo's expert report (copy), 1986 (Box-folder 64: 17)
  - Court Order Dismissing Charges, 1984 (Box-folder 64: 18)
  - Tax Form 990 hassle, 1982 (Box-folder 64: 19)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1980 (Box-folder 64: 20)
  - Investigator's report, 1981 (Box-folder 64: 21)
  - Colorado statutes, undated (Box-folder 64: 22)
  - Rozek Defense Fund, 1967-1985 (Box-folder 64: 23)
  - Bender and Treece, 1984 (Box-folder 64: 24)
  - Mrs. Booth, 1984 (Box-folder 64: 25)
  - Carney Greenstein, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 64: 26)
    Correspondence between Rozek and a divorce lawyer.
  - First police report, 1972-1983 (Box-folder 65: 1)
  - 3037.1 Rozek, Edward, documents from University offices, 1965-1981 (Box-folder 65: 2)
  - Discovery received from Topolnicki, 1981 (Box-folder 65: 3)
  - Financial statements, 1972-1974 (Box-folder 65: 4-5)
  - Harold A. Haddon, 1985 (Box-folder 65: 6)
  - Summary of dates, undated (Box-folder 65: 7)
  - Evidence used in court case, 1978-1995 (Box-folder 65: 8-9)
    Contains compact sound cassette labeled defendant's exhibit S.
  - Evidence used in court case, 1978-1995 (Box-folder 66: 1-2)
  - Court case documents, 1980-1985 (Box-folder 66: 3)
  - Court case documents 60-100, 1980-1983 (Box-folder 66: 4-8)
  - Court case documents 600, 1970-1982 (Box-folder 66: 9)
  - Court case documents, 1978-1982 (Box-folder 66: 10-11)
  - Counts 14-16, undated (Box-folder 66: 12-14)
  - Schedule, 1980-1984 (Box-folder 67: 1)
  - Investigative memos, Dr. Edward Rozek, undated (Box-folder 67: 2)
  - Count 2, undated (Box-folder 67: 3)
  - Court case documents, 1983-1984 (Box-folder 67: 4)
  - Count 11-12, 17-19, 20-22, undated (Box-folder 67: 5-8)
  - Court case documents, undated (Box-folder 67: 9)
  - Detective Topolnicki's daily log, 1980 (Box-folder 68: 1)
  - Court case documents, 1980 (Box-folder 68: 2)
  - Tax reports, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 68: 3)
  - Miscellaneous evidence, 1975-1981 (Box-folder 68: 4)
  - Case letters, 1983 (Box-folder 68: 5)
  - Legal bills, 1982 (Box-folder 68: 6)
  - Legal comments, 1984 (Box-folder 68: 7)
  - Rex John correspondence, 1983 (Box-folder 68: 8)
  - Haskins and Sells, tax exempt status of Institute, 1971 (Box-folder 68: 9)
  - Harassment, Sandy F. Kraemer, 1980 (Box-folder 68: 10)
  - Harold A. Haddon, 1982-1987 (Box-folder 68: 11)
    Correspondence between divorce lawyer and Rozek.
  - Dean Erwin N. Griswold, 1989 (Box-folder 68: 12)
  - Dill, Dill, and McAllister, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 69: 1)
  - Dill, Dill, and McAllister, 1985-1987 (Box-folder 69: 2)
  - Ahmad Ghoreischi, 1982 (Box-folder 69: 3)
  - Peter Dietze, 1983 (Box-folder 69: 4)
  - William F. Buckley, Sr., 1985 (Box-folder 69: 5)
  - Decision of the 10th Circuit Court of Appeals, 1989 (Box-folder 69: 6)
  - Motion for Extension to submit response to Topolnicki's motion for summary judgement, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 7)
  - Brief in response to motion for summary judgement, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 8)
  - Notice of Appeal to 10th Circuit Court of Appeals, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 9)
  - Colorado University, Response to Request for Documents, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 10)
  - Colorado University, Reisdorff, Supplemental Response to Request for Documents, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 11)
  - Reply Brief, 10th Circuit of Court of Appeals, 1988 (Box-folder 69: 12)
  - University of Colorado (CU), Reisdorff, Liddle, Citation of Supplemental Authority, 10th Circuit Court of Appeals, 1988 (Box-folder 69: 13)
  - CU, Reisdorff, Liddle, Brief 10th Circuit Court of Appeals, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 14)
  - Consolidated Brief to 10th Circuit Court of Appeals, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 15)
  - Status Report, 10th Circuit Court of Appeals, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 16)
  - Complaint and Demand for jury trial, undated (Box-folder 69: 17)
  - Arval Morris, 1987 (Box-folder 69: 18)
  - Dan Hale's affidavit, 1982 (Box-folder 69: 19)
  - Reply to Request for Admission, 1985 (Box-folder 69: 20)
  - Brief for Civil Suit, 1985 (Box-folder 69: 21)
  - Response to Defendant’s 3rd Request for Documents, 1986 (Box-folder 69: 22)
  - Coors' contribution to Institute, undated (Box-folder 69: 23)
  - Inventory of items returned by Topolnicki, 1984 (Box-folder 70: 1)
  - Chronology of case, undated (Box-folder 70: 2)
  - Events and schedules, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 3)
  - Official notices, rules, regulations, information, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 4)
  - Special honors by Regents, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 5)
  - Sunderland, Regent information, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 6)
  - Appointment of Topolnicki, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 7)
  - Institute records, 1978 (Box-folder 70: 8)
  - Travel authorization for Rozek's Phoenix and Washington trip, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 9)
  - Letters regarding Judd book, 1983 (Box-folder 70: 10)
  - Errol Willett, evidence from Vienna, 1983 (Box-folder 70: 11)
  - Rozek Defense Fund, 1982 (Box-folder 70: 12)
  - Rozek statement when charges made, undated (Box-folder 70: 13)
  - Beth MacParland's letter to Howard Bittman, 1982 (Box-folder 70: 14)
  - Beth MacParland's letter regarding Mindy Franklin and Frank Azar, undated (Box-folder 70: 15)
  - Letters after charges filed, J. Wallace Donald, 1983 (Box-folder 70: 16)
  - Chancellor J. Russell Nelson, 1970-1981 (Box-folder 70: 17)
  - Mindy Franklin, 1984 (Box-folder 70: 18)
  - "Letter to My Friends,", undated (Box-folder 70: 19)
  - John Stanfield, 1985 (Box-folder 70: 20)
  - Police reports, 1980 (Box-folder 70: 21-22)
  - Petition to dismiss Topolnicki, 1981 (Box-folder 70: 23)
  - Affidavits for search warrants, undated (Box-folder 70: 24)
  - Charges, 1983 (Box-folder 70: 25)
  - Responses to charges, 1983 (Box-folder 70: 26)
  - Hearing, 1981 (Box-folder 70: 27)
  - Ballots on legal fees, 1982 (Box-folder 70: 28)
  - Interrogatory of Harrigan, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 70: 29)
  - Response to discoveries, undated (Box-folder 70: 30)
  - Correspondence with John Topolnicki, 1980-1981 (Box-folder 71: 1)
  - Motion to disqualify Topolnicki, undated (Box-folder 71: 2)
  - Topolnicki's withdrawal, 1983 (Box-folder 71: 3)
  - Topolnicki's interrogations, 1985 (Box-folder 71: 4-5)
  - Minutes of the Board, 1978-1983 (Box-folder 71: 6-8)
  - American Bar Association guidelines, undated (Box-folder 71: 9)
  - Abdul Al-Sayed, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 10)
  - Blackmail, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 11)
  - Booth letter, 1977 (Box-folder 71: 12)
  - Statement from Neva Booth, 1984 (Box-folder 71: 13)
  - Doris Buffett items stolen, 1981 (Box-folder 71: 14)
  - Charles F. Brega, 1982 (Box-folder 71: 15)
  - Doris Buffett statement, 1981 (Box-folder 71: 16)
  - Mrs. Howard Buffett letter, 1980 (Box-folder 71: 17)
  - Beth MacParland's letter to Dan Hale, 1981 (Box-folder 71: 18)
  - Dan Hale letter, 1981 (Box-folder 71: 19)
  - Harold A. Haddon, undated (Box-folder 71: 20)
  - Letters from friends, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 71: 21-22)
  - Jay Lovestone, 1980 (Box-folder 71: 23)
  - McAllister, bills, 1987 (Box-folder 71: 24)
  - McAllister, correspondence, 1985-1989 (Box-folder 71: 25)
  - McAllister, Citation of Supplemental Authority 10th Circuit Court of Appeals, 1988 (Box-folder 71: 26)
- Correspondence and Memoirs, 1948-2003 (Boxes 72-75)
  Correspondence, clippings, notes, and drafts.
  - Evelyn McCabe, 1981-1986 (Box-folder 72: 1)
  - Miller, Gray and Hale, 1978-1981 (Box-folder 72: 2)
  - Charles S. Maddock Case, undated (Box-folder 72: 3)
  - Haddon Maddock, correspondence, 1984 (Box-folder 72: 4)
  - Robert Miller, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 72: 5)
  - Correspondence from case, 1981-1983 (Box-folder 72: 6)
  - Notice of intent to sue, 1983 (Box-folder 72: 7)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence, 1979-1983 (Box-folder 72: 8)
  - Invitation to victory party, 1980 (Box-folder 72: 9)
  - Letter from President Reagan, 1981 (Box-folder 72: 10)
  - Solzhenitsyn letter, 1976 (Box-folder 72: 11)
  - Solzhenitsyn file, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 72: 12)
  - Court case materials, 1976-1985 (Box-folder 72: 13)
  - Richard Spelts, 1983 (Box-folder 72: 14)
  - Documents on Russia, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 72: 15)
  - Edward Greenberg, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 73: 1)
  - Newspaper articles regarding Beth MacParland, 1987 (Box-folder 73: 2)
  - Newspaper clippings, Greenberg confirmation, 1987 (Box-folder 73: 3)
  - Recruitment memo, 1990 (Box-folder 73: 4)
  - James Corbridge, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 73: 5)
  - Gordon Gee, 1986-1990 (Box-folder 73: 6)
  - Association of Senior Professors, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 73: 7)
  - Court case documents, 1962 (Box-folder 73: 8)
  - Regents meeting, 1987 (Box-folder 73: 9)
  - Mustapha Pasha, 1988 (Box-folder 73: 10)
  - Newspaper clippings, Pasha, 1988 (Box-folder 73: 11)
  - Letters regarding Regents, 1988-1991 (Box-folder 74: 1)
  - Contributions, campaign for Regent, 1980 (Box-folder 74: 2)
  - Conference papers, 1959-1993 (Box-folder 74: 3)
  - Rozek documents, 1991 (Box-folder 74: 4)
  - Supporting material for autobiography, 1948-2003 (Box-folder 74: 5)
  - Autobiography draft pages ii-535, undated (Box-folder 74: 6-10)
  - Photos for autobiography, 1954-1980s (Box-folder 74: 11)
  - Rozek retirement clippings, 1991 (Box-folder 75: 1)
  - Chapter 5, 6-10 autobiography, undated (Box-folder 75: 2-3)
  - Chapter 7 autobiography, court case, undated (Box-folder 75: 4)
  - Autobiography and memoir materials, undated (Box-folder 75: 5)
  - Autobiography on the University of Colorado years, undated (Box-folder 75: 6)
  - Autobiography appendices, undated (Box-folder 75: 7)
  - Post-tenure review, 1985 (Box-folder 75: 8)
  - Minority Affairs Committee, 1986 (Box-folder 75: 9)
  - The W. F. Dyde Forum, 1973-1997 (Box-folder 75: 10)
  - Committee information, G.A.C. for Beer, 1977 (Box-folder 75: 11)
  - Fellowship Committee, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 75: 12)
  - Mark Lichback, 1997 (Box-folder 75: 13)
  - Vice Chancellor Loh, 1997 (Box-folder 75: 14)
- Center for Science, Technology, and Political Thought Files and Correspondence, 1951-1997 (Boxes 76-83)
  Includes correspondence, clippings, and memos. Previously known as the Edward Teller Center.
  - Teller Center speakers, newspaper clippings, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 1)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1994 (Box-folder 76: 2)
  - Income tax exempt form, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 3)
  - State of Colorado annual report and tax information, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 4)
  - Haskins and Sells financial statements, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 5)
  - Statement of expenses, 1975 (Box-folder 76: 6)
  - Teller Center Board of Directors, 1975 (Box-folder 76: 7)
  - Center files, 1980 (Box-folder 76: 8)
  - Center Board meeting, 1976 (Box-folder 76: 9)
  - Solzhenitsyn Society application forms and definition of purpose, undated (Box-folder 76: 10)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1975 (Box-folder 76: 11)
  - Original Center bylaws, undated (Box-folder 76: 12)
  - Center Board meetings, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 76: 13)
  - Contact with University of Colorado (CU), 1974 (Box-folder 76: 14)
  - Alex Brown and Sons, Center financial statements, 1995-1997 (Box-folder 76: 15)
  - Center correspondence, 1974-1979 (Box-folder 76: 16)
  - Center 990 tax form, 1975 (Box-folder 76: 17)
  - Center tax forms, 1973-1976 (Box-folder 76: 18)
  - Center balance sheets, 1975 (Box-folder 76: 19)
  - Income taxes, 1975 (Box-folder 76: 20)
  - IRS correspondence, 1975 (Box-folder 76: 21)
  - Haskins and Sells opinion on fundraiser, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 22)
  - Haskins and Sells financial statements, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 23)
  - Board of Directors and Executive Committee Advisory Council announcements, 1974 (Box-folder 76: 24)
  - Letters to Daily, Boulder Camera, and Denver Post, 1994 (Box-folder 76: 25)
  - Albino, 1992 (Box-folder 77: 1)
  - Albino controversy correspondence and documentation, 1994 (Box-folder 77: 2-3)
  - CU budget, 1995-1996 (Box-folder 77: 4)
  - Gene Nichol, 1994 (Box-folder 77: 5)
  - Albino resignation clippings, 1994 (Box-folder 77: 6)
  - Ten year budget projection, 1973 (Box-folder 77: 7)
  - Agreement between CU and the Center, 1973 (Box-folder 77: 8)
  - Middleton controversy, 1995 (Box-folder 77: 9)
  - Flores and Michaelson, 1995 (Box-folder 77: 10)
  - Bank account printouts, 1996-1997 (Box-folder 78: 1)
  - Purchase orders, 1997 (Box-folder 78: 2)
  - Center bills, 1997 (Box-folder 78: 3)
  - Dyde forum purchase orders, 1996 (Box-folder 78: 4)
  - Dyde forum bills, 1996 (Box-folder 78: 5)
  - Dyde forum, 1987-1997 (Box-folder 78: 6)
  - Center tax return, 1976 (Box-folder 78: 7)
  - Center tax return, 1980 (Box-folder 78: 8)
  - Center tax documents, 1979-1981 (Box-folder 78: 9)
  - Agreement between Colorado University and the Center, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 78: 10)
  - Articles of incorporation, 1974 (Box-folder 78: 11)
  - Bylaws and articles of incorporation, 1975 (Box-folder 78: 12)
  - Analysis of the power structure of the faculty senate, 1973 (Box-folder 78: 13)
  - Board meeting minutes, 1976 June 22 (Box-folder 78: 14)
  - Proposal for the establishment of the Center for the Comparative Study of Political Systems and Ideologies, 1971 (Box-folder 78: 15)
  - Haskins and Sells correspondence, 1974 (Box-folder 78: 16)
  - Arthur Andersen, 1977-1979 (Box-folder 78: 17)
  - Exemption from federal income tax, 1974 (Box-folder 78: 18)
  - Budget and Finance Committee, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 79: 1)
  - Haskins and Sells report, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 2)
  - Budget and Finance Committee, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 3)
  - Advisory council agenda, 1975 (Box-folder 79: 4)
  - Budget and Finance Committee meeting minutes, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 5)
  - Budget and Finance Committee meeting minutes, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 6)
  - Joint meeting of Board of Directors and Advisory Council, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 7)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 8)
  - Site selection minutes, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 9)
  - Board of Directors amendments to the articles of incorporation, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 10)
  - Board of Directors agenda, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 11)
  - Board of Directors meeting, 1973 (Box-folder 79: 12)
  - Board of Directors amendments to the bylaws, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 13)
  - Board of Directors resolution regarding the Executive Committee, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 14)
  - Haskins and Sells financial statements, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 15)
  - Memorandum report Board and counsel members Teller Center, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 16)
  - Board of Directors meeting minutes, 1975 (Box-folder 79: 17)
  - Board of Directors, 1978 (Box-folder 79: 18)
  - Unit I, Graphic Design, 1974 (Box-folder 79: 19)
  - Income taxes, 1976 (Box-folder 79: 20)
  - Teller Center documents, 1972 (Box-folder 80: 1-2)
  - Notes on ideology, undated (Box-folder 80: 3)
  - Notes and clippings, 1969 (Box-folder 80: 4)
  - Apollo 17 promotional material, 1969 (Box-folder 80: 5)
  - Transcript of court document, 1962 (Box-folder 81: 1)
  - Clippings, 1962 (Box-folder 81: 2-4)
  - Publications, 1960-1667 (Box-folder 81: 5)
  - Sidney Hook speeches, undated (Box-folder 81: 6)
  - Dyde Forum, 1962-1967 (Box-folder 81: 7)
  - Allan C. Brownfeld, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 81: 8)
  - Reprints, 1969 (Box-folder 81: 9)
  - Regiment in Poland, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 81: 10)
    Includes documents in Polish.
  - Troubles, 1964 (Box-folder 81: 11)
  - Correspondence with Colorado University administrators, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 81: 12)
  - Documents and clippings, 1968-1991 (Box-folder 81: 13)
  - Correspondence with students, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 82: 1)
  - Colorado University Regent articles of incorporation, 1968 (Box-folder 82: 2)
  - Salaries, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 82: 3)
  - Clippings, 1987-1995 (Box-folder 82: 4)
  - Clippings, 1963 March (Box-folder 82: 5)
  - Quigg Newton, 1961-1963 (Box-folder 82: 6)
  - Vietnam, 1965 (Box-folder 82: 7)
  - Lectures, 1951-1956 (Box-folder 82: 8)
  - Manning clippings, 1966 (Box-folder 82: 9)
  - Clippings, 1963 (Box-folder 82: 10)
  - Guest speakers, 1976 (Box-folder 82: 11)
  - Letters after Goldwater speech, 1962 (Box-folder 82: 12)
  - William O. Winter, 1966 (Box-folder 82: 13)
  - Budget Committee minutes, 1968 (Box-folder 83: 1)
  - Freedom House, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 83: 2)
  - Dyde Forum, 1967 (Box-folder 83: 3)
  - Clippings, 1963 April-May (Box-folder 83: 4-5)
  - Anti-Red clippings, 1959 (Box-folder 83: 6)
  - Radio Free Europe correspondence regarding employment, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 83: 7)
  - Clippings, 1962 February-March (Box-folder 83: 8-9)
  - Merle Fainsod, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 83: 10)
  - Seminar notes and papers, 1961-1969 (Box-folder 83: 11-15)
- Teaching and Research Materials, 1953-1994 (Boxes 84-92)
  Clippings, notes, correspondence, articles, and drafts of writings.
  - "The American Network," article by A. T. Jordan, undated (Box-folder 84: 1)
  - Teaching materials, undated (Box-folder 84: 2)
  - Teaching materials regarding Soviet foreign policy, 1953-1990 (Box-folder 84: 3)
  - Notes on Warsaw Treaty, undated (Box-folder 84: 4)
  - "The Life of Nikola Petkov,", undated (Box-folder 84: 5)
  - Materials regarding Yugoslavia, undated (Box-folder 84: 6)
  - Notes, undated (Box-folder 84: 7)
  - Notes regarding Comecon, 1980s (Box-folder 84: 8)
  - Political science teaching materials, 1963 (Box-folder 84: 9-10)
  - Notes, 1990s (Box-folder 84: 11-12)
  - Handwritten notes regarding Yugoslavia, undated (Box-folder 85: 1)
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 85: 2)
  - Teaching materials regarding Czechoslovakia, undated (Box-folder 85: 3)
  - Notes and clippings regarding Germany and Russia, undated (Box-folder 85: 4-9)
  - Notes regarding Britain and France, undated (Box-folder 86: 1-7)
  - Comparative governments, undated (Box-folder 87: 1-4)
  - Notes regarding Russia, 1970s (Box-folder 87: 5-6)
  - American defense, undated (Box-folder 87: 7)
  - News from Behind the Iron Curtain, Vol 4, No. 3, 1955 (Box-folder 87: 8)
  - Clippings regarding Eastern Europe, 1959-1966 (Box-folder 87: 9)
  - "The Origin of National Communism" by Roman Smal-Stocki, 1958 (Box-folder 87: 10)
  - Miscellaneous notes, 1964 (Box-folder 88: 1)
  - Lecture notes regarding World War II and communism, undated (Box-folder 88: 2)
  - Handwritten notes regarding communism, undated (Box-folder 88: 3)
  - Clippings and notes regarding Poland, 1980-1982 (Box-folder 88: 4)
  - Handwritten notes regarding Bulgaria, undated (Box-folder 88: 5)
  - Notes regarding Eastern European countries, undated (Box-folder 88: 6)
  - Russian Research Center seminar notes, 1964 (Box-folder 88: 7)
  - Clippings and papers, 1962-1988 (Box-folder 88: 8)
  - Teaching materials, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 88: 9)
  - "Henry Kissinger: Architect of an American Tragedy" by Edward Rozek, 1979 (Box-folder 88: 10)
  - Handwritten notes, "The Search for Security,", undated (Box-folder 88: 11)
  - Handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 88: 12)
  - "The Pattern of Post-Stalinist Foreign Policy," handwritten notes, undated (Box-folder 88: 13)
  - Teaching notes and materials, 1992 (Box-folder 88: 14)
  - Tadeusz Maslowski correspondence, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 89: 1-2)
  - Tadeusz Maslowski documents, 1993-1994 (Box-folder 89: 3)
  - "Profile in Academic Courage" by Ann Donnelly, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 89: 4)
  - Correspondence and teaching materials, 1966 (Box-folder 89: 5)
  - Correspondence, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 89: 6)
  - Clippings, 1963 February (Box-folder 89: 7)
  - Edward Rozek v. Samuel E. Christensen [et al.], undated (Box-folder 89: 8)
  - Associated Alumni, 1962 (Box-folder 89: 9)
  - Clippings and correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 89: 10-12)
  - Dayton correspondence, 1962 (Box-folder 90: 1)
  - Clippings and correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 90: 2)
  - Bromley-Newton controversy, 1962 (Box-folder 90: 3)
  - Clippings, 1962 August (Box-folder 90: 4)
  - Clippings and correspondence, 1962 (Box-folder 90: 5-6)
  - Court case document, petition of Edward J. Rozek for the perpetuation of testimony, undated (Box-folder 90: 7)
  - Publications by Edward Teller, "Western Democracy on Trial," "The Miracle of Freedom," "Freedom in the Age of Technology" and "Three Hundred Million," published by the Institute for the Comparative Study of Political Systems and Ideologies, 1972 (Box-folder 90: 8)
  - "Dr. Edward Rozek, PhD," pamphlet, undated (Box-folder 90: 9)
  - "Democracy on Trial: The Battle for Boulder," and "Academic Freedom and Academic Anarchy" by Sidney Hook, published by the Institute for the Comparative Study of Political Systems and Ideologies, 1969 (Box-folder 90: 10)
  - Tri-State Fossil Fuels Energy Conference proceedings, 1974 (Box-folder 90: 11)
  - "The Strategic Surrender of the United States" and "Revolutionary Warfare as an Instrument of Policy" by Sir Robert Thompson, undated (Box-folder 90: 12)
  - Information booklet regarding the Center for Science, Technology, and Political Thought, undated (Box-folder 91: 1)
  - Clippings and correspondence, 1978-1994 (Box-folder 91: 2)
  - Articles, undated (Box-folder 91: 3)
  - Correspondence, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 91: 4-13)
  - The Academic Underworld: How the Inner Core Runs a University by Edward Rozek, manuscript pages 1-391, undated (Box-folder 92: 1-4)
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 92: 5)
  - Walter Judd papers, 1978 (Box-folder 92: 6)
  - Walter Judd interview by Paul Hopper, 1968 (Box-folder 92: 7)
  - Correspondence and clippings, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 92: 8)
- Books and Booklets, 1948-2005 (Box 93)
  Various books and booklets in English and Polish.
  - John L. Cooreman, 1948 (Box-folder 93: 1)
  - Poland: A Study in Treachery; Confucius: His Life, Thought, and Influence; and Polish Government in Exile, booklets, 1989-1996 (Box-folder 93: 2)
  - Placowka Armii Krajowej Tyszowce by Ireneusz Caban, 1999 (Box-folder 93: 3)
  - Pamiec I tozsamosc by Jan Pawel II, 2005 (Box-folder 93: 4)
  - Czarne Kwiaty Biale Kwiaty, 1996 (Box-folder 93: 5)
  - Humanism i teologia by Werner Jaeger, 1957 (Box-folder 93: 6)
  - Struna Swiatla by Zbigniew Herbert, 1994 (Box-folder 93: 7)
  - Motyl na Sniegu by Janusz Kazimierz Zawodny, 2004 (Box-folder 93: 8)
  - Ksiegi Narodu Polskiego by Adam Mickiewicz, 2004 (Box-folder 93: 9)
  - Noc na kremlu by Ksawery Pruszynski, 1989 (Box-folder 93: 10)
  - Trebacz Samar z Kandy by Ksawery Pruszynski, 1983 (Box-folder 93: 11)
- First Polish Armoured Division Materials, 1979-2001 (Boxes 93-95)
  Various materials regarding the First Polish Armoured Division, including the Pancerniak Newsletter.
  - First Polish Armoured Division Veterans Association materials, 1989-1997 (Box-folder 93: 12)
  - Pancerniak Newsletter, no. 14-54, 1979-1995 (Box-folder 94: 1-8)